关了
Turn it off.
(我们对你失去亲人深表遗憾)
这附近的行尸比以前要多了
There's more of them around here than there used to be.
- 不知道是否有人… - 嘘
- Don't know if any people are... - Shh.
是有人
Someone is.
《行尸走肉》
艾登想从一只行尸嘴下
Aiden was trying to save us
救出我们
from a roamer,
他对它开枪
shooting at it.
然后格伦让他分心了
Then Glenn distracted him.
我看见了手榴弹
I saw the grenades.
我想阻止他
I tried to stop him.
他们想跑 我不想
They wanted to just go, I didn't.
他想跑
He was gonna run.
我不想丢下他
I wasn't gonna leave him.
塔拉呢？
What about Tara?
我也不想丢下她
I wasn't gonna leave her.
但我们逼他留了下来
But we made him stay.
没人帮忙的话 救不出艾登
Couldn't get Aiden out of there without help.
然后我们进入大厅时
Then when we got into the lobby...
他只用抵住门就行
All he had to do was hold the door.
他敲打着玻璃
He was hitting on the glass,
推开我的门
pushing my door open.
他们要杀了我
They were gonna kill me.
但他惊慌失措了
But he panicked.
或者说他们想杀我 也许他们压根不在乎
Or they were trying to. Or they just didn't care.
诺亚 我抓住他了
Noah, I had him.
我抓住他的手了
I had his hand.
如果我不往回推
And if I didn't push back,
我也会死的
I'd be dead, too.
我尽力了
I tried.
我眼睁睁看着他死去
I watched him die.
是他们干的
They did this.
是他们
It was them.
但你们一起回来了
But you all came back together.
那是怎么回事？
How did that happen?
妈 你在干什么？
Mom, what are you doing?
我稍后要看录像 我们现在就得拍
I need it for later. We have to do this now.
不许带枪 不许出去
No guns. No going outside the walls.
格伦也是 直到我调查清楚
Same goes for Glenn until I finish looking into this.
你要调查什么啊？
What do you need to look into?
我都跟你说了事情的经过
I... I'm telling you how it went down.
这些人必须离开
These people have to go.
他们跟我们不一样
They are not like us.
我知道你也看出来了
I know you see it, too.
你不知道我看到了什么 尼古拉斯
You don't know what I see, Nicholas.
我看得很清楚
And I see a great deal.
我差点就把他留在那里了
I almost left him out there.
可以编个故事糊弄过去
Could have told a story.
怎么 你觉得我应该那样做吗？
What, you think I should have?
他们不知道自己在干什么
They don't know what they're doing.
- 没有一个人知道 - 我们可以教他们
- Any of them. - We'll show them.
我不知道他们能不能看清现实
I don't know if they can see it. How things really are.
我不知道他们能不能做到
I don't know if they can yet.
他们还没有认清事实
They haven't caught up.
我们必须留在这里
We have to be here.
- 我们必须留下 - 没错 我们必须
- We have to. - Yeah, we do.
但是他们的规矩 我们不必遵守
But their rules, we don't answer to them.
我们就是他们 瑞克
We are them, Rick.
如今是了
We are now.
诺亚 他对这里很有信心
Noah, he believed in this place.
我告诉你 我们必须在这里好好生活
I'm telling you, we gotta make this work.
我送了烤面到迪安娜家
I sent a casserole to Deanna's family.
要让她看到我们的关心
We want her to see that.
你想过皮特吗？
Have you thought about Pete?
还有我说的那件事吗？
About what I said?
想过
Yeah.
我又和山姆谈了谈
Talked to Sam some more.
他说他妈妈在壁橱里安了插销
He said his mom put a bolt on the inside of his closet.
有时她会叫他把自己锁在里面
Tells him to lock himself in sometimes
直到早上才能出去
and not come out till morning.
他说他能听见他爸在吼
He said he can hear his dad yelling,
摔东西 他妈妈在哭
things breaking, his mom crying.
上个月有一次忽然没声了
Last month it got quiet right in the middle of it
他走出去发现妈妈躺在地上
and he went out and found her on the floor
昏迷了 流着血
unconscious, bleeding.
皮特坐在门廊上无动于衷
Pete was just sitting on the porch.
你为什么这么关心杰茜的遭遇？
Why do you care what happens to Jessie?
你知道原因的
You know why.
而且我知道你为什么关心她
And I know why you do.
为什么？
Why?
我见过你和她聊天的样子
I've seen you talk to her.
假如行尸没有杀死爱德
If walkers hadn't gotten Ed,
我现在就不会站在这里了
I wouldn't be standing here right now.
不 你会的
Yeah, you would.
瑞克
Hey, Rick.
Rick.
你没事吧 伙计？
You okay, man?
继续走
Keep walking.
什么？
What?
你在说什么…
What are you...
请进
Come in.
- 她怎样了？- 稳定下来了
- How is she? - Stable.
撑着呢 我一会儿回去
Hanging on. I'm gonna go back there later.
我觉得萨沙可能在哨塔里过了夜
I think Sasha might have spent the night in the tower.
她还在上面吗？
Is she still up there?
现在是亚伯拉罕在值班 但是
Abraham's on watch now, but...
她没回来 没人见过她
she hasn't been back and nobody's seen her.
就在前面
It's up ahead.
她告诉你的吗？
She told you about it?
有一天我见到她拿着步枪出去了
I saw her going out one day with her rifle.
我知道已经有人放哨了 我问了她
I knew somebody was already in the tower. I asked.
这是我们来这里之后我第一次出来
It's the first time I've been out since we've been here.
我也是
Me, too.
我已经感觉到不一样了
It already feels different.
这是好事
That's good.
不好说
I don't know.
在发现
After Eugene,
尤金说谎之后
after finding out he lied,
我感到很迷惘
I was screwed up
因为我失去了希望
because I lost something.
而你似乎因为找到了希望而迷惘
You seem screwed up because we found something.
诺亚死了
Noah's dead.
而我觉得
And I think...
在那里我仿佛一直在沉睡
I just feel like I was asleep in there.
你是在努力忘掉过去 重新开始
You were trying to forget so you could try.
- 我不想忘掉过去 - 那就别忘
- I don't want to forget. - So don't.
但这不意味着你要放弃
But that doesn't mean you have to give up.
你没有带上你的刀
You didn't bring your sword with you.
这已经能说明问题了
That's not nothing.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry for what happened.
你还好吗？
How are you holding up?
不好
I'm not.
我们应该处理一下皮特的问题
We have a problem with Pete.
我还以为状况会好转
I hoped it'd get better.
你知道吗？
You knew?
状况并没好转 以后也不会
It hasn't gotten better. It won't.
皮特是外科医生
Pete's a surgeon.
他救了很多人
He's saved lives.
他也可能救下塔拉的命
He might be saving Tara's life.
他在对妻子施暴
He's beating his wife.
- 我们必须制止他 - 怎么制止？
- We have to stop it. - How?
我们让他们分居
We separate them.
告诉他必须遵守
We tell him that's how it'll be from now on.
如果他不愿意 你会怎么办？
What happens when he doesn't want to do that?
他别无选择
It's not his choice.
你会怎么办？
So what happens?
我会杀了他
I kill him.
我们杀了他
We kill him.
我们不能随便杀人
We don't kill people.
这里是文明社会 瑞克
This is civilization, Rick.
警告别人住手 否则就得死
Warning someone to stop or die,
那才是如今的文明
that is civilized nowadays.
所以呢？我们就放任他施暴吗？
So what? So we just let him hit her?
让他弄死她吗？
We let him kill her?
不 如果真那样 我们就流放他
No, we exile him if it comes to that.
如果那么做 我们不知道他什么时候会摸回来
We do that, we don't know when he comes back
会做出什么事来
and what he does to them.
放走他
Letting him go
只会让这里岌岌可危
makes this place vulnerable.
你真想等到塔哨上的警卫
You really want to wait till someone in that tower
不得不出手的时候吗？
has to take care of it?
- 那还得是我们走运的情况下 - 我们不会…
- And that's if we're lucky. - We are not...
处死任何人
executing anyone.
别再提这种建议了
Don't ever suggest it again.
这种想法不允许存在于此
That sort of thinking doesn't belong in here.
现在出人命是家常便饭 迪安娜
People die now, Deanna. They do.
在这种危急时刻
There's times like this
你可以决定谁死 什么时候死
you can decide who and when.
否则别人可能会替你做决定
Or it can be decided for you.
已经有人替我做过了
It already was.
换做你 我也不会杀你
I wouldn't kill you.
只会流放你
I'd just send you away.
从后脑击穿的
Got it in the back of the head.
肯定是她
Had to be her.
后脑
Back of the head.
她在猎捕它们
She's hunting them.
卡尔
Carl.
我知道你在跟踪我
I know you're following me.
又一次
Again.
而且你方向错了
And you're going the wrong way.
你早知道吗？
You knew?
因为你动静太大了
You're very loud.
你能回去吗？
Can you go back?
说实话 你吓到我了
To be honest, you scare me.
你不应该自己溜出来
You shouldn't sneak out by yourself.
刚死了两个人
Two people just died.
拜托
Oh, come on.
总有人会死的 你知道的
People always die. You know that.
我们该回去了
We should go back.
为什么？
Why?
你到底跑这来干什么？
What do you do out here anyways?
跟你一样
Same thing as you.
尼古拉斯 什么也别说 听着就行
Nicholas, don't talk, just listen.
那次外出时送命的四个人
Those four people you lost on that run,
都归咎于你
that's on you.
而诺亚的死
And Noah,
也是你的错
that's on you, too.
那五条人命
Those five lives,
都是你造的孽
you have to carry that.
像你这样的人 早该死了
People like you are supposed to be dead,
但幸好这些墙及时建起
but these walls went up just in time,
所以你还没死
so you're not.
你不准再踏出墙外半步
You don't go outside those walls anymore.
不准单独出去 也不准跟任何人出去
Not by yourself, not with anyone else.
这样你才能活下来
And that's how you're gonna survive.
你他妈以为你是谁？
Who the hell do you think you are?
我是一个了解你本性的人
I'm someone who knows who you are.
我知道你做过什么
I know what you did.
我不会再让这种事发生
And it's not gonna happen again.
我一直尽心尽力保护这里
I've been protecting this place,
帮忙供给 而你才刚来而已
helping provide for it. You just got here.
别忘了我刚说过的话
Don't forget what I said.
你是在威胁我吗？
Are you threatening me?
不
No.
我是在救你
I'm saving you.
我们就该待在外面
We're supposed to be out here.
我们就该拥有这种感觉
We're supposed to feel like this.
我不想忘记这种感觉
I don't want to forget.
奔跑 让我感觉好过些
And .. running makes me feel better.
我忘不了
I can't forget.
我会梦到
I dream about it.
跟它们一起置身于森林之中
Being in the forest with them.
我也是
I do, too.
罗恩是个好人
Ron's a good guy.
是啊
He is.
他知道你跑出来了吗？
Does he know you come out here?
不知道 我…
No, I...
他不会理解的
he wouldn't understand.
你为什么会怕我？
Why do I scare you?
我也不知道 就是怕
I don't know. You just do.
刀不错
Cool knife.
曾是我妈的刀
It was my mom's.
你在到达那里之前 经历了什么？
What happened to you before you got there?
那重要吗？
Does it matter?
重要 我懂的
It does. I know.
我也经历过一些可怕的事
Something bad has happened to me, too.
我们得走了 听起来有很多行尸
We need to go. Sounds like a lot.
这是它们的世界
It's their world.
我们只是活在其中而已
We're just living in it.
很好
Cool.
你也怕我
You're afraid of me, too.
萨沙
Sasha.
你们回去
Go back.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我受够了被动防守
I'm sick of playing defense.
所以你要主动干掉它们吗？
So you're just gonna take on all of them?
是的
Yeah.
我们得离开这里
We've got to get out of here.
你们走吧 我没事
Oh..You do, I don't.
- 我不需要你的帮助 - 不是为了你
- I don't need your help. - This isn't for you.
我自己能行的
I had it.
不需要你帮忙
Don't need your help.
我都让你们走了
I told you to go.
你…
You...
你什么都做不了
you can't do anything.
你挺适应这一切的
It worked out for you.
你没发现吗？
Don't you see that?
你帮不了我
You can't help me.
没有人
Nobody...
诺亚
Noah.
我告诉过他他活不下去
I told him he wouldn't make it.
行凶者把剩下的躯体带走了
Whoever did this took what was left with them.
这是刚发生的
This just happened.
她被绑了起来
She's tied up.
然后他们吃了她
And they fed on her.
撕裂她
Tore her apart.
这也是刚发生的吗？
This just happened?
是的
Yeah.
怎么会这样？
How the hell did this happen?
杰茜
Jessie.
我不想让罗恩和山姆知道我抽烟
I don't want Ron and Sam to know about those.
我会保密的
Your secret's safe.
诺亚是个好孩子
Noah was a sweet kid.
但是塔拉 皮特把她照顾得很好
But Tara, she's... she's in good hands with Pete.
他打了你
He's hitting you.
他伤害了你
He's hurting you.
这必须停止
It has to stop.
- 会停止的 - 为什么？
- It will. - How?
他以前经历过一些事
There are things in his life that happened.
我不在乎
I don't care.
听我说 以前也是这样
Look, it was like this before
但他后来听劝改了
and he got help.
我劝他改了
I helped him
情况后来变得很好
and things were good.
我可以处理好的
I can fix it.
不 你做不到 但我可以
No, you can't. But I can.
不 你能做什么？
No, what... what can you do?
你要怎么做 要把他关进监狱吗？
What are you gonna do? You gonna put him in jail?
你只会把情况搞得更糟
You're only gonna make things worse.
如果情况恶化 那意味着他已经杀了你
If it's gotten worse, it means he's killed you.
那就是接下来会发生的事
That's what's next.
我不会让那种事发生的
And I'm not gonna let that happen.
你为什么会在乎？
Why do you care?
为什么这事对你那么重要
Why is this so important to you?
现在 你好不容易安定下来
Now? You've made it.
你为你的孩子们找到了一个家
You have a home for your kids.
瑞克 你到底想干什么？
Rick, what are you doing?
我只是想帮忙而已
I'm trying to help.
我看未必
I don't know that.
我已经结婚了
I'm married.
明白吗？我可以管好自己
Okay? I can take care of myself.
我们都得管好自己
We have to take care of ourselves.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你知道山姆找人要枪了吗？
You know Sam asked for a gun?
为了保护你
To protect you.
你不该来这里的
You shouldn't be here.
杰茜 在这里 你看不清状况
Jessie, in here, you can't see it,
但其实是一样的
but it's the same.
其实跟外面的世界是一样的
It's the same as out there.
我们有食物吃 有房子住
We have food and roofs over our heads,
但你不能苟且偷生
but you don't get to just live.
你不能忍气吞声
You don't get to put it off
或是祈祷一切好转 杰茜
or wish it away, Jessie.
如果你不抗争 你就会死掉
If you don't fight, you die.
而且…
And...
我不希望你死
and I don't want you to die.
我可以帮助你
I can... I can help you.
我可以保障你和孩子们的安全
I can keep you and your boys safe.
我可以做到的
I can.
你只需要点头答应就行
All you have to do is say yes.
你会为别人做这种事吗？
Would you do this for someone else?
换做是别人 你还愿意这么做吗？
Would you do this for anyone?
不 不会
No. No.
我同意
Yes.
瑞克
Rick.
你来干什么？
What are you doing here?
皮特
Pete.
你来这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
- 听我说 - 我得请你走人了 瑞克
- Listen to me. - I'm gonna have to ask you to leave, Rick.
不要
No.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
该离开的人是你
You need to leave.
你在胡说什么？
What are you talking about?
走吧 皮特
Just go, Pete.
你们刚刚谈了些什么？
What have you been saying to each other?
你们两个干了什么好事
What have you been doing!
皮特 我们都出去吧
Pete, you and me are gonna leave now.
你跑到我家来…
You come into my house...
皮特 我们出去吧
Pete, you and me are leaving.
该出去的人是你
You're leaving right now.
你以为你代表了法律吗？
You think you're the law?
你真以为这里轮得到你做主吗？
You actually think you have a say in anything here?
- 退后 - 你以为你是谁啊？
- Step back. - Who the hell do you think you are?
我在忍着不杀你
Someone who's trying not to kill you.
不
No!
你最好住手
You wanna stop now!
敢跑进我家
Come into my house!
- 皮特 住手 - 这是我家
- Pete, stop it! - It's my house!
皮特 住手
Pete, stop it!
不 住手
No! Stop it!
迪安娜
Deanna!
爸 别打了
Dad, get off!
住手
Stop it!
立刻住手
Stop it right now.
再敢碰他们 我就杀了你
You touch them again and I'll kill you.
该死 瑞克 我说了停手
Damn it, Rick! I said stop.
不然呢？
Or what?
你要赶我走吗？
You gonna kick me out?
放下枪 瑞克
Put that gun down, Rick.
你还是不懂
You still don't get it.
你们都不懂
None of you do!
我们知道该怎么做 我们从不迟疑
We know what needs to be done and we do it.
我们是幸存者
We're the ones who live.
你们只会呆坐着 定计划和犹豫
You, you just sit and plan and hesitate.
你们装作什么都懂 其实什么也不懂
You pretend like you know when you don't.
你们只会希望世界不是这个样子
You wish things weren't what they are.
你们想活下去吗？
Well, you want to live?
你们想让这地方维持下去吗？
You want this place to stay standing?
你们那套结束了
Your way of doing things is done.
事情不是想想就会变好
Things don't get better because you... you want them to.
从现在开始 我们必须
Starting right now, we have to live
活在现实中
in the real world.
我们必须审核谁能待在这里
We have to control who lives here.
我现在非常清楚谁能待在这里
That's never been more clear to me than it is right now.
我吗？你…
Me? Me? You...
你是说我吗？
You mean... you mean me?
你的方法会毁掉这里
Your way is gonna destroy this place.
会害死人
It's gonna get people killed.
已经害死人了
It's already gotten people killed.
我不能坐视不理
I'm not gonna stand by and let it happen.
不抗争
If you don't fight,
就会死
you die.
我不能袖手旁观…
I'm not gonna stand by...